Finding Aid for the Joyce A. Fadem Papers LSC.1109
UCLA Library Special Collections
Joyce A. Fadem papers
1959-1967
UCLA Library Special Collections
Fadem, Joyce A.
LSC.1109
5.0 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
Joyce Abrams Fadem (b.1932) was a educator and a prominent member of the California Democratic party. She served as director of political action and legislation for the California Teachers Association, Los Angeles (1969-71), was a member of the California Democratic State Central Committee (1960-64 and again, beginning in 1966), secretary of the California Democratic Council (CDC) Board of Directors (1963-67), and a member of the Los Angeles Democratic County Central Committee (1966-76). Her publications include The public secondary school pupil and the case law of California (1961). The collection consists of correspondence, minutes of board meetings, official records, documents, printed materials, ephemera, and tape recordings relating to the organization and activities of the California Democratic Council (CDC) during the period Joyce Fadem served as secretary to the board of directors. Included is the only complete tape recorded record of the 1967 and 1968 CDC annual conventions documenting the critical Vietnam War debates and the removal of President Simon Cassidy from office.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Joyce Fadem, 1971.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942330013606533
We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.
Biography
Joyce Abrams Fadem was born on February 25, 1932 in Los Angeles; attended UC Berkeley, 1949-50; AA (1951), BA (1952), MA (1961), UCLA; teacher, University High School (Los Angeles), 1953-57; training teacher in the teacher training program, UCLA, 1955-57, 1959-60; faculty member, social science Department, Los Angeles City College, 1962-69; instructor, Immaculate Heart College, 1967-69; director of political action and legislation, California Teachers Association, Los Angeles, 1969-71; member, California Democratic State Central Committee, 1960-64 and again, beginning in 1966; secretary, California Democratic Council (CDC) Board of Directors, 1963-67; member, Los Angeles Democratic County Central Committee, 1966-76; publications include The public secondary school pupil and the case law of California (1961).
Biographical Narrative
Mrs. Joyce Fadem has been active in California Democratic Politics for several years, serving as a member of the California Democratic State Central Committee from 1960-1964 and 1966 to the present. She has also been a member of the Los Angeles County Central Committee since 1966.
This collection, given by Mrs. Fadem in November 1971, contains the official records, documents, and correspondence, as well as the unofficial correspondence, of the California Democratic Council during the period Mrs. Fadem served as secretary to the CDC Board of Directors, 1963-1967.
(Who's Who in American Politics, 1971-1972)
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, minutes of board meetings, official records, documents, printed materials, ephemera, and tape recordings relating to the organization and activities of the California Democratic Council (CDC) during the period Joyce Fadem served as secretary to the board of directors. Includes the only complete tape recorded record of the 1967 and 1968 CDC annual conventions documenting the critical Vietnam War debates and the removal of President Simon Cassidy from office.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Collection is arranged chronologically.
Related Material
Knox Mellon California Democratic Council papers (Collection 1061). Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Charles G. Gant California Democratic Council Records (Collection 1073). Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Joseph L. Wyatt Collection of California Democratic Council Records (Collection 1082). Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
California Democratic Council Records (Collection 1389). Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Women political activists -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Teachers -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; California Democratic Council; Fadem, Joyce A.--Archives.
- CDC Minute Book., 1959-1961. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Dollars for Democrats., 1959. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Membership drive., 1960-1962. (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Organization committee., 1960. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- CDC (Miscellaneous)., 1961. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Communication committee., 1961-1965. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Convention (CDC)., 1961. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Organization committee., 1961. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Convention (CDC)., 1962. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Organization committee., 1962-1963. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Election campaign., 1962. (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- CDC (Miscellaneous)., 1963. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Board of Directors meeting., May 1963. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Board of Directors meeting., June 1963. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Board of Directors meeting., September 1963. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Board of Directors meeting., November 1963. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Board of Directors roll call., 1963-1965. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence and minutes., March-June 1963. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Finance., 1963. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- CDC Headquarters., 1963-1965. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Headquarters and personnel., 1963-1966. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Los Angeles County Democratic Clubs., 1963. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Tenth Birthday (CDC)., 1963. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Board of Directors meeting., January 1964. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Board of Directors meeting., April 1964. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Board of Directors meeting., June 1964. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Board of Directors meeting., September 1964. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Board of Directors meeting., November 1964. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Convention (CDC)., 1964. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Convention - Planning., [1964]. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Convention - Speeches., [1964]. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Election (Primary)., [1964]. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Election (General)., [1964]. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Finance (Dollars for Democrats)., 1964. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Local endorsements., [1964]. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Slate mailer., 1964. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Assembly district representatives., 1965. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors meeting., January 1965. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Board of Directors meeting., April 1965. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Board of Directors meeting., June 1965. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Board of Directors meeting, Special., August 7, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Board of Directors meeting., September 1965. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Board of Directors meeting., October 1965. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Board of Directors meeting., November 1965. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Board of Directors lists., 1965-1967. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Board of Directors roll call., 1965-1967. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Board meeting minutes (attachments to)., 1965-1966. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Casady - correspondence relating to., 1965. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Casady - Majority caucus., 1965-1966. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Convention (CDC)., 1965. (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
- Convention - Candidates., [1965]. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Convention - Delegate kits., [1965].; (2 kits) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Convention - Planning., [1965]. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Executive committee., [1965]. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Finance (Dollars for Democrats)., 1965. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Governor's Education Conference., [1965]. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Post convention., [1965]. (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Press and speeches., [1965]. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Program planning committee., [1965-1966]. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Resolutions., [1965-1966]. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Tally and nomination petitions., [1965-1966]. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Board of Directors meeting., January 1966. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Board of Directors meeting., February 1966. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Board of Directors meeting., April 1966. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Board of Directors meeting., June 1966. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Board of Directors meeting., September 1966. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Board of Directors meeting., November 1966. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Constitution and by-laws., 1966. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Convention (CDC), Issues committee., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Convention - Planning., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
- Convention - Roster., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Convention - Speeches, press, etc.., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Election (Primary) campaign and slate mailer., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Endorsement and challenges., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Executive Board., 1966. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Finance., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Majority caucus (ex-)., 1966. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- New Politics Movement., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Post convention., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Registration., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Resolutions., [1966].; (draft copies) (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Tallys., [1966]. (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Board of Directors meeting., November 1966.; (1 tape) (Box 9)
- Convention (CDC)., 1966.; (10 tapes) (Box 9)
- Board of Directors meeting., February 1967. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors meeting., April 1967. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Convention (CDC)., March 1967. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Convention., 1967.; (7 tapes) (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Convention (Special)., September 1967. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Peace slate (Anti-CDC)., 1967. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- "What is CDC?" (Material for a history of CDC)., [1967]. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- CDC (Miscellaneous)., 1967-. (Box 10, Folder 6)
- California Observer (vol.1, no.1-vol.2, no.1)., 1965-1966. (Box 10, Folder 7)